AHMAD AL-AHMAD

Personal Information:

Address: Farnborough, Hampshire

Mobile Number: +44 7763240867

Email Address: ahmad.younes.2005@gmail.com https://github.com/freshcoder1983

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ahmad-al-ahmad-b54885149

Portfolio: www.ahmad-alahmad.tk
Portfolio vz.o: www.ahmad-alahmad.tk

Profile:

I am a hard-working, quick-learner, and highly-motivated individual with excellent communication skills and more than 8 years experience in IT Desktop Support. I am able to work in a team or individually depending on the task. I am a sociable, friendly, organised and reliable person to work with and ambitious to learn about new technologies.

Qualifications:

- Gained CompTIA A+ Certificate.
- In addition to my current role, I am pursuing my ambition to learn and gain professional qualifications in web development. I gained:
 - MTA (98-383): Introduction to Programming Using HTML and CSS Certificate.
 - MTA (98-375): HTML5 Application Development Fundamentals Certificate.
 - MTA (98-382): Introduction to Programming Using JavaScript Certificate.
 - CIW (Certified Internet Web Professional 1Do-620): Advanced HTML5 and CSS3 Specialist Certificate.
- Preparing for the following exams:
 - CIW (Certified Internet Web Professional): JavaScript Specialist.
 - CCNA (CISCO Certified Network Associate).
 - MCSA: Web Applications leading towards MCSD: App Builder.

Work Experience:

January 2018 – August 2018

ICT Technician, Yateley School, UK:

Yateley School is the largest secondary school in North East Hampshire. The school teaches over 1500 students aged 11 – 16, and the attached sixth form college caters for ages 16–18.

Responsibilities:

- Provide first level software and hardware support to users (Teachers, School Staff and Students).
- Manage tickets using a help desk software called Spiceworks.
- Install, modify, and repair computer hardware and software and install computer peripherals.
- Using Bradfords Network Network Sentry software to allow users to connect wirelessly to the internet.
- Imaging and re-imaging desktops and laptops using WDS (Windows Deployment Service).
- Creating users accounts using Active Directory.
- Email creation, configuration, delegation and mailbox size increasing using Microsoft Exchange Server 2013.
- Microsoft Outlook 2013 troubleshooting.
- Anti-Spam and Web filtering using Smoothwall.
- Creating accounts and resetting passwords using Microsoft Office 365.
- Liaising with suppliers emailing suppliers with requests for quotations to cover new equipment purchases.
- IP phones management using Splicecom manager.
- Local Group Policy management.
- PCs remote access using AB Tutor and RDC (Remote Desktop Connection) or RDP.
- Antivirus Deployment, installation and management using Webroot Antivirus package.
- Network cabling, testing and tracing using the appropriate network tools.
- Designing email signature using HTML.

14/11/2011 – 04[/]02/2016

IT Technician, Civil Aviation Authority, Qatar:

The Civil Aviation Authority of Qatar (QCAA) is the government agency responsible for licensing, monitoring, and regulating civil aviation matters. It is administered by the Qatar Ministry of Transport and Communications.

Responsibilities:

- Knowledge of Anti-Viruses and perform scanning for malicious Viruses and treating infected computer systems.
- Troubleshooting, configuring, and installing of Microsoft products (Windows 7/8/8.1/10 and Office Suite) and other popular software products on desktops and laptops.
- Configure, install and set up network printers, shared printers and peripheral devices.
- Familiar with LAN structure as I am able to solve and troubleshoot technical network connectivity and dealing with users issues.
- Troubleshoot and resolve basic issues with voice communications (VoIP Telephones such as CISCO phones) and mobile phones.
- Coordinate with vendors or technicians for service and support.
- Providing technical assistance and support for incoming queries and issues relating to computer systems, software, and hardware.
- Designed and developed intranet website for the company using web programming languages such as HTML, HTML5, CSS, CSS3, basic JavaScript
 with jQuery, basic MySQL, and basic PHP.

31/07/2011 - 03/11/2011

Help Desk Specialist, Ali Bin Ali Group (Technology Solutions Division), Qatar:

Ali Bin Ali Technology Solutions (ABATS) is one of the leading IT Systems Integrators in Qatar offering a variety of competitive and innovative business solutions and services.

Responsibilities:

- Respond to queries for customers seeking help by phone, email or by using the help desk software called Portal and Ensure proper recording, documentation and closure.
- Provide first level contact and convey resolutions to customer issues.
- Properly escalate unresolved queries to the next level of support.
- Ask questions to determine nature of problem.
- Walk customers through problem-solving process.
- Install, modify, and repair computer hardware and software and install computer peripherals.
- Out of hours on-call support once a week.
- During my work, the company have sent me outsourcing to Al-Jazeera for 1 month as a Help Desk Specialist to provide some assistance with the help desk team in the premises.

2009 – 2011

IT Desktop Supervisor, Al-Qadisia Travel and Tourism, Syria:

Responsible for complete system support including software and hardware maintenance and functionality. I also took responsibility for the front office on many occasions and dealt directly with clients. This required **courtesy** and familiarity with the travel agency systems and processes, which I quickly learnt and worked with, without supervision.

Responsibilities:

- Troubleshooting, configuration, installation of Microsoft Windows XP/2000/Vista/7 OS on desktops and laptops.
- Setup computers and install software for various applications and programs.
- Maintain computer peripheral devices like printers and resolve associated problems.
- Responsible for monitoring, operating, managing, troubleshooting and restoring to service any personal computers (PC) or notebooks that has authorized access to the network.

2002 - 2003

IT Technician Swaileh Computer Store, Jordan:

I worked without supervision in dealing with customer IT issues. It was my responsibility to see each enquiry through from initial customer consultation to successful solution. Customers commented on both my knowledge and friendly approachable character. I worked in the maintenance of computers, as well as sales, and servicing. I dealt with customer needs and helped maintain the shop floor to present the products in the best way possible. I enjoyed assisting customers and satisfying their needs.

Responsibilities:

- Build, install, repair and maintain PCs, laptops, and computer peripherals.
- Test and verify hardware and manage peripherals to ensure that they meet specifications and requirements.
- Support Microsoft Windows and Office Suite.
- Provide high level of customer care.

Education:

2001 – 2006

Philadelphia University, Jordan: BSc in Computer Engineering. (GPA 71.5%)

Skills:

Languages:

- English Fluent.
- Arabic Native.

• Key Skills:

- Excellent communication skills, both written and verbal.
- Strong troubleshooting skills.
- Microsoft Windows and Microsoft Office.
- HTML, HTML5.
- CSS, CSS₃.
- Basic Bootstrap 3 and Bootstrap 4.
- Basic SASS.
- Basic JavaScript.
- Basic jQuery.Basic MySQL.
- Basic PHP.
- Active Directory and Group Policy.
- Web hosting and domain registration.
- Basic Adobe Photoshop.
- Basic Adobe Dreamweaver.